Finding Aid to the Atherton Seidell Papers, 1899-1986
History of Medicine Division, National Library of Medicine.
Atherton Seidell Papers 1899-1986
Seidell, Atherton, 1878-1961
1.26 linear feet (3 boxes)
MS C 399
History of Medicine Division. National Library of Medicine
Consists of printed matter, notes, and miscellaneous papers. Includes reprints (1899-1937), minutes of meetings of the Chemical Society of Washington (1904-1906), and research notes.
Provenance
Unknown.
Restrictions
Collection is not restricted. Contact the Reference Staff for information regarding access.
Biographical Note
Atherton Seidell introduced microfilming into the Army Medical Library in the 1930s. The research notes were probably for a future edition of Seidell's book, Solubilities of inorganic and organic compounds.
Collection Summary
Consists of printed matter, notes, and miscellaneous papers. Includes reprints (1899-1937), minutes of meetings of the Chemical Society of Washington (1904-1906), and research notes.
Index Terms
These terms are indexed in the National Library of Medicine's online catalog LocatorPlus. Researchers wishing to find related materials should search the catalog using these terms.
MeSH Subjects
Chemistry; Solubility
Corporate Names
Chemical Society of Washington (Washington, D.C.)
Series Descriptions
- Series I: Biographical Information, 1986
  - Biographical materials, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1928-1938
  - Correspondence regarding research, 1928-1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series III: Chemical Society of Washington, 1904-1906
  - Meeting minutes - Seidell secretary, 1904-1906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Reprints of Seidell Articles, 1899-1937
  - "Some chemical principles involved in making a photographic negative" - in The Engineering Society Annual, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Chemical publications of A. Seidell 1901-1910" [list of 1-30], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Reprints 1-9, 1901-1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reprints 10-20 [no. 16 omitted], 1905-1908 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reprints 21-30, 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reprints, 1911-1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Reprints, 1914-1925 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reprints, 1926-1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series V: Notes, n.d.
  - Article citations, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Apparatus and methods [microfilm of articles with notes], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Duplicate Russian [microfilm of articles with notes], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
  - Duplicate Russian [microfilm of articles with notes], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous [microfilm of articles with notes], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2-4)